A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Staff seminar on public management in Peru, Novemer (Reports 016710), 1973 (Box 856, Reel R-9320)
  07390807
  Research and training in the social sciences for the Andean region.
  Public administration -- Peru; Economics -- Political aspects -- Peru
- Background information on Indonesia, Philippines and Thailand (Reports 016711), 1989 (Box 856, Reel R-9320)
  Economic development -- Southeast Asia; Economics -- Political aspects -- Southeast Asia
- Briefing notes on the Thailand Upland Social Forestry Project (Reports 016712), 1989 (Box 856, Reel R-9320)
  08700536
  Support documentation and research on pilot projects in community forest management in northeast Thailand.
  Social forestry programs -- Thailand; Forests and forestry -- Social aspects -- Thailand; Uplands -- Thailand, Northeastern; Upland ecology -- Thailand, Northeastern; Deforestation -- Thailand, Northeastern; Agroforestry -- Thailand, Northeastern
- Rural poverty and resources programming in Thailand (Reports 016713), 1988 (Box 856, Reel R-9320)
  Social forestry programs -- Thailand; University cooperation -- Thailand; Rural development -- Thailand; Agriculture -- Research -- Thailand; Agriculture and state -- Thailand
- The Senegal, Mali and Ivory Coast ports of Jim Ellis' West Africa trip (Reports 016714), 1982 (Box 856, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to Tyler Biggs dated March 17, 1982 (corrected and retyped on March 19, 1982).
  Charity organization -- Africa, West; Endowments -- Africa, West; Community organization -- Africa, West; Human rights -- Africa, West
- Trip report: Guinea, April 1-3 (Reports 016715), 1985 (Box 856, Reel R-9320)
  File memo dated April 19, 1985.
  Education, Higher -- Guinea; Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Guinea
- Human rights, governance and international affairs in West Africa (Reports 016716), 1988 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Political stability -- Africa, West; Human rights -- Africa, West; Law -- Study and teaching -- Africa, West; Legal services -- Africa, West; Law reform -- Africa, West
- The Middle East in international politics (Reports 016717), 1982 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to William Carmichael and Enid Schoettle dated August 23, 1982.
  Arab-Israeli conflict -- 1973-1993; International relations -- Arab countries; Political stability -- Arab countries; Endowments -- Arab countries
- Trip report - Gaborone, Botswana, December 6-11 (Reports 016718), 1979 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated December 19, 1979.
  Refugees -- Botswana; Refugees -- Services for -- Botswana; Refugees -- South Africa; Education, Higher -- Botswana; College students -- Botswana; Scholarships -- Botswana
- Visit to Somalia (Reports 016719), 1982 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to William Carmichael, et al. dated June 18, 1982.
  Public administration -- Research -- Somalia; Refugees -- Somalia; Repatriation -- Somalia; Political stability -- Somalia; Human rights -- Somalia
- International Conference on Population, Mexico City, August 6-14 (Reports 016720), 1984 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to colleagues dated September 21, 1984.
  International Conference on Population (1984: Mexico City, Mexico)
  Population -- Congresses; Population assistance -- Congresses; Population policy -- Congresses
- State of affairs in Kenya (Reports 016721), 1982 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to William Carmichael dated August 30, 1982
  Political stability -- Kenya; Public administration -- Kenya; Human rights -- Kenya
- A participatory approach to irrigation development: experience from the Philippines (Reports 016722), 1982 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  "... prepared for the "Participative Planning and Management" panel at the American Society for Public Administration Convention, Honolulu, March 22, 1982." -- T.p.
  08200733
  Support research and training related to the enhancement of farmer roles in irrigation development and management in the Philippines.
  Irrigation projects -- Philippines; Irrigation -- Government policy -- Philippines; Irrigation farming -- Philippines; Agricultural development projects -- Philippines; Agriculture -- Research -- Philippines
- Visit to Nairobi (Reports 016723), 1980 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to David Smock dated April 30, 1980.
  Education and Public Policy (EPP)/Education & Research
  Education -- Research -- Kenya; Women -- Education -- Kenya; Non-formal education -- Kenya; Women -- Kenya -- Social conditions; Literacy -- Kenya; Academic achievement -- Kenya
- The situation in Ethiopia (Reports 016724), 1984 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to William Carmichael and Peter Geithner dated December 7, 1984.
  Developing Countries Program/Eastern & Southern Africa
  Emergency management -- Ethiopia; Disaster relief -- Ethiopia; Economic assistance -- Ethiopia; Endowments -- Ethiopia
- Zimbabwe up-date (Reports 016725), 1983 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Memo to William Carmichael and Peter Geithner dated March 21, 1983.
  Political stability -- Zimbabwe; Politics and war -- Zimbabwe; Human rights -- Zimbabwe; Public administration -- Zimbabwe; Non-governmental organizations -- Zimbabwe
- Management of social transformation at national and sub-national levels (Reports 016726), 1981 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Social change -- Philippines; Social learning -- Philippines; Social planning -- Philippines; Public administration -- Philippines; Community development -- Philippines
- Report on a visit to Cairo and Tanta, March 10th through March 23rd, 1985: Submitted to the Ford Foundation Regional Office, Cairo, Egypt (Reports 016727) (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Business enterprises -- Egypt; Small business -- Egypt; Community development -- Egypt
- Report of the External Advisory Panel on Education to the World Bank (Reports 016728), 1978 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Banks and banking -- Study and teaching -- Developing countries; Bank employees -- Training of -- Developing countries; Education, Higher -- Finance -- Developing countries
- Report of the External Advisory Panel on Education to the World Bank draft (Reports 016729), 1978 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
- Strengthening Foundation accountability: summary of the Vector III recommendations (Reports 016730), 2006 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  "A considerable amount of discussion focused on the need to respond effectively to the growing public interaction in the operation of the not-for-profit sector, to improve the capacity to design and develop effective program strategies and to communicate […]Recommendations formulated by the Vector III Task Force on strengthening program accountability practices and corresponding final report.
  Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Evaluation; Nonprofit organizations -- United States -- Evaluation
- Ethiopia - changes at the horizon? (Reports 016731), 1983 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Endowments -- Ethiopia -- Evaluation; Social sciences -- Research -- Ethiopia; Education, Higher -- Ethiopia; Women graduate students -- Ethiopia
- The U.S. position on torture: its implications for U.S. foreign policy and human rights: panel discussion (Reports 016732), 2006 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  February 22, 2006 panel discussion transcribed from CD with panelists: Mike Posner, Admiral John Hutson, Ann Beeson and Morton Halperin.
  Torture -- United States; Political prisoners -- United States; Human rights -- United States
- The Ford Foundation fellowships for minorities, 1980-2004 (Reports 016733), 2006 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Minorities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Scholarships -- Research -- United States; Minorities -- Education -- United States -- Statistics; Education, Higher -- Social aspects -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance
- Professional development, curriculum standards and program data centralization: black studies advancements project (Reports 016734), 1993 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  08801165
  The National Council for Black Studies, Inc.
  To provide support for summer institutes and administrative training workshops in black studies for college and university faculty members.
  African Americans -- Study and teaching -- Curricula; Blacks -- Study and teaching -- Curricula; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation; Education, Higher -- United States; College teachers -- Training of -- United States
- Remarks regarding career education (Reports 016735), 1972 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Speech given at a conference sponsored by the Educational Testing Service (ETS) in Washington, D.C. on May 12, 1972.
  Career education -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Professional education -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Education -- United States; School-to-work transition -- United States
- The communications program: options for the 1980s (Reports 016736), 1978 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Journalism -- United States; Communication policy -- United States; Mass media -- Law and legislation -- United States; Public television -- United States
- The hidden medium: educational radio: a status report (Reports 016737), 1967 (Box 857, Reel R-9320)
  Radio in education -- United States -- Finance; Educational radio stations -- United States -- Finance; Radio broadcasting -- United States; Radio in community development -- United States
- The future of educational telvision: analysis and recommendations (Reports 016738), 1962 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  06200196
  WGBH Educational Foundation
  Exchange of live programs between the educational television stations in Boston and New York City.
  Educational television programs -- United States; Television in education -- United States; Educational television stations -- United States; Radio in education -- United States
- Mandatory origination requirement for cable systems: Prepared under a grant from the Ford Foundation (Reports 016739), 1974 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  07300557
  Support to expand the communications policy program and for part of the work to be done by Henry Geller.
  [Report] - Rand Corporation;R-1548-FF
  Cable television -- United States; Television broadcasting -- United States; Communication policy -- United States
- Television and society: a position paper (Reports 016740), 1978 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Television broadcasting -- Social aspects -- United States; Television broadcasting policy -- United States; Television programs for children -- United States
- The future of cable television: some problems of federal regulation (Reports 016741), 1970 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  06990481
  Support for a study by the Rand Corporation on cable TV.
  Rand Corporation. Memorandum RM-6199-FF
  Television broadcasting -- United States; Cable television -- United States; Television relay systems
- Trip report on the African Philanthropy Initiative retreat in Jinja, Uganda, April 8 (Reports 016742), 2004
  "The main purpose of the trip was to attend the summative conference of the Foundation's seven-year African Philanthropy Initiative (API)...We hoped to see the level of philanthropic work and determine the next level and kind of engagement by the Foundati
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS);Peace and Social Justice
  African Philanthropy Initiative Retreat (2004 March 29 - April 1: Jinja, Uganda)
  Endowments -- Africa; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Africa
- Cable television: the problem of local monopoly (Reports 016743), 1970 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Support for a study by the Rand Corporation on cable tv.
  Rand Corporation. Memorandum RM-6309-FF
  Television broadcasting -- United States; Cable television -- United States; Public television -- United States; Television relay systems
- A brief history of educational television in the United States: with emphasis on the development of National Educational Television and the concept of public television (Reports 016744), 1968 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  History of educational television
  Television in education -- United States -- History; Public television -- United States -- History
- Cable television: options for Jacksonville volume one (Reports 016745-001), 1973 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Identifies likely service demands, outlines alternative systems, specifies financial and technical differences between alternatives, and clarifies cable television regulatory situation as it relates to the City of Jacksonville. -- from introductory p. ii.
  Cable television -- Florida -- Jacksonville (Fla.); Public broadcasting -- Florida -- Jacksonville (Fla.); Television relay systems -- Florida -- Law and legislation -- Florida; Cable television -- United States
- Cable television: options for Jacksonville, volume two (Reports 016745-002), 1973 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
- The viewing of public television -- 1970, November 1970: Prepared for the Corporation for Public Broadcasting (Reports 016746) (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Public broadcasting -- United States -- Statistics; Public television -- United States; Television viewers -- United States -- Statistics; Broadcast journalism -- United States -- Statistics
- Profit making ventures and public television stations: a report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 016747), 1971 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Television in education -- California -- San Francisco (Calif.); Public television -- California -- San Francisco (Calif.) -- Finance; Public broadcasting -- California -- San Francisco (Calif.) -- Finance; Public-access television -- California -- San Francisco (Calif.)
- Communications act of 1978: H. R. 13015: briefing materials for the Ford Foundation meeting (Reports 016748) (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  H,. R. 13015
  Telecommunication -- Law and legislation -- United States; Broadcasting -- Law and legislation -- United States; Communication and traffic -- Law and legislation -- United States
- Human resources and the pendulum of power: Connecticut Social Welfare Conference, November 18 (Reports 016749), 1976 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Education and Research/Public Policy and Social Organization
  Public welfare -- Political aspects -- United States -- Congresses; Public welfare -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Human services -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Humanitarianism -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.
- Statement of Fred W. Friendly on H. R. 13015 before the Subcommittee on Communications, Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, United States House of Representatives (Reports 016750), 1978 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Transcript of speech given before U.S. House of Representatives, September 26, 1978.
  Statement before Subcommittee on Communications
  Telecommunication -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Public broadcasting -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.; Communication and traffic -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Speeches, addresses, etc.
- Statement of McGeorge Bundy on H.R. 13015 before the Subcommittee on Communications, Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, United States House of Representatives (Reports 016751), 1978 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
- Report on Israel #2 (Reports 016752), 1979 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Report on nine-day visit to Israel, January 5-13, 1979 (follow-up to a report produced as a result of an eight-day trip in June, 1978) -- p.1.
  Arab-Israeli conflict -- 1967-1973
- Statement of Fred W. Friendly, advisor on television, the Ford Foundation, before the Committee on Finance, United States Senate (Reports 016753), 1974 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Transcript of speech given before United States Senate Committee on Finance, September 10, 1974.
  Statement before the Committee on Finance
  Telecommunication -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Speeches in Congress; Public broadcasting -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Speeches in Congress; Public television -- Law and legislation -- United States -- Speeches in Congress
- Report on the meeting on mid-career fellowships (Reports 016754), 1974 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Scholarships -- United States -- Congresses; Journalism -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- United States; Reporters and reporting -- Study and teaching -- United States
- Using television for teaching a second language through dramatized every day situations: an assessment of effects on active speech and on understanding dialogues presented by other media (Reports 016755), 1971 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Television in speech education -- Israel -- Evaluation; Television in secondary education -- Israel -- Evaluation; English language -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- Hebrew speakers -- Evaluation; English language -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- Israel
- Before the Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights, Senate Committee on the Judiciary, statement, October 12 (Reports 016756), 1971 (Box 858, Reel R-9320)
  Transcript of speech given before U.S. senate Committee on the Judiciary, October 12, 1971.
  Statement before the Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights
  Public broadcasting -- Law and legislation -- United States; Communication policy -- United States; Freedom of speech -- United States
- Conference on impact of media on political campaigning (Reports 016757), 1973 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Mass media -- Political aspects -- United States; Political campaigns -- United States
- Analysis of the CBP-PBS-FF negotiations with respect to the establishment of the station program cooperative (Reports 016758), 1974 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  CPT-PBS-FF Negotiations
  Public broadcasting -- United States -- Finance; Public television -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States
- Statement of McGeorge Bundy to Subcommittee on Communications and Power, Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, U.S. House of Representatives (Reports 016759), 1973 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Transcript of speech given before Subcommittee on Communications and Power, June 12, 1973.
  Statement to Subcommittee on Communications and Power
- A study to determine the feasibility of a live public radio network (Reports 016760), 1968 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Tab 1. Summary -- Tab 2. Budget.
  06800571
  National Association of Educational Broadcasters
  Study on feasibility of establishing a regional public radio network.
  Feasibility of a live public radio network
  Radio broadcasting -- United States -- Feasibility studies; Radio in education -- United States -- Finance; Educational radio stations -- United States -- Finance
- Book publishing and the first amendment: report of a conference (Reports 016761), 1975 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Report of conference held April 18-20, 1975 at the Harrison Inn, Southbury, Connecticut. Co-Sponsors: Association of American Publishers, Inc. (Freedom to Read Committee) and Ford Foundation.-- T.p.
  Humanities & Arts program
  Book publishing and the 1st Amendment
  Publishers and publishing -- United States -- Congresses; Publishers and publishing -- United States -- Case studies
- Foundation conference on Japan (Reports 016762), 1972 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Memo from Eugene Staples dated March 27, 1972.
  Conference on Japan.
  Economic development -- Japan; Education, Higher -- Japan; Communication -- Japan; Endowments -- Japan
- Grantmakers resource handbook 2006 (Reports 016763), 2005 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Handbook prepared by Grantcraft aimed at assisting funders with awards and management of grants.
  Grant craft
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Finance; Endowments -- Program-related investments
- Transforming an American region: recommendations for a Gulf Coast development initiative (Reports 016764), 2005 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  A management report to the Ford Foundation. -- T.p.
  Charity organization -- Gulf Coast (U.S.); Community development -- Gulf Coast (U.S.); Economic development -- Gulf Coast (U.S.); Disaster relief -- Gulf Coast (U.S.); Education, Higher -- Gulf Coast (U.S.); Public schools -- Gulf Coast (U.S.)
- The role of foundations in public broadcasting, II: the Ford Foundation (Reports 016765), 1977 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Public broadcasting -- United States -- Finance; Public television -- United States -- Finance; Television in education -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- United States
- Ford in black higher education (Reports 016766), 1973 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Copy of article from March 1973 Race Relations Reporter.
  African American universities and colleges -- Finance; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Finance; Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- United States
- Media and communications at a crossroads: the role of scholarship for media reform and justice (Reports 016767), 2006 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Media and communications at a crossroads: the role of scholarship for media reform and justice: January 20, 2006: Ford Foundation, New York
  Mass media -- Research grants -- Congresses; Mass media policy -- United States -- Congresses; Intellectual freedom -- Congresses; Digital media -- Congresses; Electronic publications -- Congresses; Endowments -- United States
- Making conservation work for poor and disadvantaged natural resource-dependent communities (POM) (Reports 016768), 2006 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  10600445
  International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources (IUCN)
  For research, meetings and workshops to make conservation a core asset for livelihood security in Eastern Africa.
  Natural resources -- Co-management -- Africa, Eastern; Energy conservation -- Africa, Eastern; Natural resources -- Management -- Africa, Eastern; Community development -- Africa, Eastern
- Increasing access to safe and supportive educational institutional institutions for girls and young women and improving public discourse and policy on gender, sexuality and HIV/AIDS, February 2006 (POM) (Reports 016769) (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  10650730
  Urgent Action Fund for Women's Human Rights (Africa)
  For a series of activities to expand the space for dialoguing and organizing for sexual minorities in East Africa.
  Sex instruction -- Africa, Eastern; Sex role -- Africa, Eastern; Reproductive health -- Africa, Eastern; AIDS (Disease) -- Africa, Eastern; Sexually transmitted diseases -- Africa, Eastern; Sexual orientation -- Africa, Eastern; Endowments -- Africa, Eastern
- Affinity Group for Development Finance: 2003 survey of members: summary of findings (Reports 016770) (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Community development -- United States; Community development -- Developing Countries; Development credit corporations -- United States; Development credit corporations -- Developing countries; Social planning -- United States; Social planning -- Developing countries
- Policy winds and exchange flows: Forty years of US - Cuban academic and educational exchanges (Reports 016771), 2006 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Teacher exchange programs -- United States; Teacher exchange programs -- Cuba; Student exchange programs -- United States -- History; Student exchange programs -- Cuba -- History; Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- Cuba
- Cross-site synthesis of findings, conclusions and key lessons: assessment of the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative (Reports 016772), 2005 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  Report describing the history and evolution of the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative (SFAI).
  09900548
  Fiscal Policy Institute, Inc.
  Grants to state-level organizations for budget and tax analysis under the state fiscal analysis initiative.
  State Fiscal Analysis Initiative
  Public administration -- United States; Political planning -- United States -- Research; Fiscal policy -- United States; Taxation -- United States
- Towards enhanced work on conflict: A consultancy for the Ford Foundation (Reports 016773), 2001 (Box 859, Reel R-9320)
  10100273